# **Dominique DeMoe**

Email: <a href="mailto:dominique.demoe@gmail.com">dominique.demoe@gmail.com</a> | Philadelphia, PA 19107

LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/dominiquedemoe/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/dominiquedemoe/</a>

GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/domdemoedesigns">https://github.com/domdemoedesigns</a>

### **Summary**

Detail oriented data visualization specialist with a passion for analyzing and cleaning data to tell a cohesive story. Proficient working independently and collaborating with teams across multiple disciplines to synthesize information from a wide variety of sources and effectively break down concepts to display for an audience. Strong design background utilizing Python and data visualization tools such as JavaScript and D3.js to clean and visualize data.

#### **Technical Skills**

**Programming Languages:** Python, JavaScript, HTML5, SQL, NoSQL **Applications:** GitHub, MySQL, MongoDB, GIT, AWS, Flask, Command Line

Tools: Excel, Jupyter Notebook, Plotly, Bootstrap, D3.Js, Leaflet, Illustrator, Photoshop

## **Projects**

ETL Project | https://github.com/domdemoedesigns/ETL-Process

Research potential data sources, analyze and clean data

- Provided users with happy hour special data on a number of different restaurants in the Philadelphia region.
- Gathered restaurant data and extracted relevant information. Looped through each restaurant on the website and created a dictionary for each restaurant's information. Utilized mongoDB to organize data.
- Tools/Languages: Python, BeautifulSoup, MongoDB

#### Philadelphia Housing Dashboard

https://github.com/jeremybar32093/philadelphia\_housing\_dashboard

Create dashboard utilizing bootstrap, clean and organize data

- A python Flask application that houses a website to perform a high level analysis and exploration of the Philadelphia housing market over the past 5 years.
- The dashboard allows the user to get an overall idea of the housing market in recent years by displaying the number of homes sold, the amount of money exchanged for home sales and summary statistics of each year.
- Tools/Languages: Python, HTML, JavaScript, CSS, SQL database

# **Experience**

## Philadelphia Inquirer

Nov. 2019 - Present

Graphics Reporter

Philadelphia, PA

- Driven traffic to website through multi-functional projects
- Implemented a new system for submitting graphics requests to streamline process
- Attend meetings with managers and editors to offer judgement and advice on what our department can do

Hallow May 2019 - Present

**Project Consultant** 

Chicago, IL

- Create briefs for design team to create social posts
- Derive data-driven suggestions for new social posts and stories
- Develop a quarterly social report

The Observer March 2018 - March 2019

**Graphics Editor** 

South Bend, IN

- Led a team of seven graphic designers to create compelling graphics for print and online production for Notre Dame's student run daily newspaper
- Collaborated weekly with members of the Editorial Board and Graphics Department to set
   Observer wide and departmental goals and to minimize nightly production time
- Photographed, directed and designed featured editions of the Irish Insider

#### Education

# **Data Analytics Certificate**

University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA 2021

• A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in Excel, VBA, Python, R, JavaScript, SQL Databases, Tableau, Big Data, and Machine Learning.

Bachelor of Arts in Design, Minor in Computing and Digital Technologies (CDT)

University of Notre Dame, South Bend, IN 2019